adeelchowdhry.com 2014-09-18

# Privacy Policy » Adeel Chowdhry

AdeelChowdhry.com [hereinafter referred to as "I", "Company", "AC", "us" or "we"] collect personal information about you and distribute that information to provide you with services and products you request on this website. In addition, we distribute that information to others to provide you with other products and services. This summary and the full policy below describes how information is collected and distributed and your choices with respect to your personal information. Please review the entire Privacy Policy for detailed information on our information and privacy practices.

#### 1\. Purpose of this Policy

This policy gives the following information about personal data:

  * What information we collect from you;
  * Where we keep it;
  * Why we collect it;
  * How we use it; and
  * Your rights in relation to it.

#### 2\. What information may we collect from you?

We may collect and process the following data about you:

Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site www.adeelchowdhry.com (our site). This includes information you provided at the time of registering to use certain elements of our site, subscribing to our services, posting material or requesting further services.

We may also ask you for information when you enter a competition or promotion sponsored by IS, and when you report a problem with our site;

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;

We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them;

Details of transactions you carry out through our site or via other means (e.g. telephone orders) and of the fulfillment of your orders;

You can access the site home page and browse the site without disclosing personal information. We collect standard Internet log information and details of visitor behavior patterns to help us identify things such as the number of visitors to the various parts of our site. We collect this information in a way which does not identify anyone (please see our [Cookie Policy](http://adeelchowdhry.com/cookie-policy/) for more details);

Communication and usage data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access. We may also use this data for diagnostic purposes, for planning and capacity management and to assist us in the prevention or detection of faults and/or misuse. We do not collect the content of emails that you have sent or received or keep a record of individual web pages that you have visited.

#### 3\. Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staffs operating outside the EEA who work for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfillment of your order and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

In addition, if you place your personal information on publicly available parts of our site, this will be accessible to people in countries outside of the EEA. Such countries may not have data protection laws as comprehensive as those that exist within the EEA.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

#### 4\. Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you (where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes);
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * To allow you to participate in any interactive features of our services, if you choose to do so;
  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer; and
  * To notify you about changes to our service.

We may also use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (email or SMS) with information about goods and services similar to those which were the subject of a previous sale to you. If you are not a customer we will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, please contact us at info [at] adeelchowdhry [dot] com.

#### 5\. Disclosure of your information

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

In order to fulfill your order for goods or services;

To enable us to provide maintenance, engineering or troubleshooting services to you in connection with goods or services supplied to you;

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;

If AC or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets;

If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or

To protect the rights, property, or safety of AC, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

#### 6\. Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also change your preferences at any time on our Customer Portal via email to info [at] adeelchowdhry [dot] com.

#### 6.1. Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. You can find out what information we hold about you by making a Subject Access Request under the Act. If we hold personal information about you we will give you a description of it, tell you why we are holding it and let you have a copy of it.

#### 6.2. Updating or amending information

If any of the personal information that we hold about you is incorrect or needs updating, or if you want us to delete any personal information, please contact us. We may request that you provide further information and identification to enable us to comply with this request.

#### 7\. Third party links on our website

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, affiliates and other third parties.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

#### 8\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. This policy was last updated on 27 June 2014.

#### 9\. Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy should be addressed to our Data Protection Compliance Manager at AdeelChowdhry.com, 122 Hither Green Lane, London, SE13 6QA
